A Guide to the Clifton Waller Barrett Erskine Caldwell Papers, 1964-1978
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Clifton Waller Barrett Erskine Caldwell Papers 1964-1978
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6526-f
This collection consists of 32 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift to the library on 1980 Dec 12.
Contents List
- Letters
  - Virginia [Caldwell] to Cornelia [Barrett], enclosing 4 photographs of the Caldwells and Clifton Waller Barrett, w/envelope 1976 Oct 8, 1 p
  - Virginia [Caldwell] to Waller [Barrett] 1976 Oct 12, 2 p
  - Virginia [Caldwell] to Cornelia and Waller [Barrett] enclosing 4 photographs and ANS, n.d., Monroe Wheeler to Cornelia Barrett and Clifton Waller Barrett, 1 p., w/envelope 1976 Dec 4, 4 p
  - Erskine Caldwell to [C] Waller [Barrett] 1977 Jan 18, 1 p
  - Virginia Caldwell to Cornelia and C. Waller [Barrett] 1977 Jan 21, 2 p
  - Virginia [Caldwell] to Cornelia and C. Waller [Barrett] 1977 Mar 25, 2 p
  - Virginia [Caldwell] to Cornelia and Waller [Barrett] 1977 Aug 25, 1 p
  - Erskine [Caldwell] to Waller Barrett, w/envelope 1977 Sep 2, 1 p
  - Erskine [Caldwell] to Waller Barrett 1977 Oct 4, 1 p
  - Erskine [Caldwell] to Waller Barrett 1977 Nov 9, 1 p
  - Virginia [Caldwell] to Cornelia [Barrett], w/envelope 1977 Nov 12, 1 p
  - [Virginia Caldwell] to Waller [Barrett], enclosing TLS (electrostatic copy), 1977 Oct 6, Arnold Herstand to Virginia Caldwell, 1p.; TMemo, n.d., by EC, 1 p.; and printed announcements of publications by EC, 2 pp. 1977 Nov 16, 2 p
  - Erskine [Caldwell] to Waller [Barrett], w/envelope [1977] Nov 26, 1 p
  - Virginia [Caldwell] to Cornelia [Barrett], w/envelope 1977 Dec 5, 3 p
  - Virginia [Caldwell] to Waller [Barrett] 1978 Jul 2, 2 p
  - Virginia [Caldwell] to Cornelia and Waller [Barrett] 1978 Aug 15, 2 p
  - Erskine [Caldwell] to Waller [Barrett] 1978 Oct 31, 1 p.
  - Erskine Caldwell to Waller [Barrett] 1978 Nov 17, 1 p
  - Virginia [Caldwell] to Cornelia and Waller [Barrett] 1978 Dec 3, 2 p
  - Virginia [Caldwell] to Cornelia and Waller [Barrett], w/envelope 1978 Dec 25, 3 p
  - Erskine [Caldwell] to Waller [Barrett], enclosing newspaper clipping (electrostatic copy), 1978 Dec 18, w/TNS at bottom, w/envelope 1978 Dec 26, 1 p
  - Virginia [Caldwell] to [Cornelia and Waller Barrett] n.d., 1 p
  - [Virginia Caldwell] to [Cornelia and Waller Barrett] n.d., 1 p
- Photographs
  - Erskine Caldwell, signed by EC 1978 Jun
  - Erskine Caldwell n.d.
  - Erskine Caldwell and C. Waller Barrett n.d.
- Miscellaneous Papers
  - S. P. Rosenbaum to C. Waller Barrett enclosing reprints of two articles on Henry James and a radio talk by Alvin Langdon Coburn (electrostatic copy) 1964 Apr 6, 4 items
  - Four letters to C. Waller Barrett re his collections 1976 May 14-Aug 26, 4 items
  - Request to C. Waller Barrett from old Sturbridge Village for loan of portrait enclosing loan agreement form 1976 Nov 18, 3 items
  - Lesley Frost Ballantine to Cornelia and Waller [Barrett] with two Christmas cards, 1974 and 1976 1976 Christmas, 3 items
  - Leon Edel to Waller [Barrett] on verso of proof for Henry James memorial program at Westminster Abbey 1977 Jan, 1 item
  - Francis Berkeley, Jr. to Waller [Barrett] 1977 Nov 25, 1 p
  - W[arren Chappell] to Cornelia and Waller [Barrett] enclosing a 1950 poem (electrostatic copy) and an illustration (pen and ink sketch) for The Adventure of Tom Sawyer and Huckleberry Finn1978 Apr 1, 3 items